So much software is yet to be produced
that like we now have the option to do
because implementation is so cheap.
>> I am talking about why CICD is dead.
When you think about how engineers are
using traditional CICD tools, those were
built for humans pre-cloud and you get
this massive volume stuck in PRs that we
never saw with humans.
>> Now we're seeing about 1300 pull
requests without human assistance be
generated and land per week.
>> You can't have so many different agents
taking versions of the same code and
merging them.
>> The AI Native Dev is a podcast for
developers and engineering leads at the
cutting edge of AI and agentic coding.
Join your hosts Guy Pajani [music] and
me Simon Maple every week as we chat
with the most exciting voices in AI and
tackle the biggest [music] questions
facing developers today.
This is the AI Native Dev.
>> [music]
>> Back in November, we hosted the first
[music] ever in-person AI Native DevCon
in New York. This June 1st and 2nd,
we're [music] bringing it to London.
It's two days built for AI Native
developers and engineering teams.
>> [music]
>> One day full of hands-on workshops and
one day full of practical talks on agent
skills, [music]
context engineering, agent orchestration
and enablement platforms, and how teams
are actually shipping AI in production.
>> [music]
>> Join us at the brewery in London near
the Barbican for all of that plus
networking, parties, giveaways, [music]
and a room full of people building the
future of AI Native development. You can
also join us from anywhere [music] in
the world via the live stream. As you're
listening to this podcast, you get 30%
off your ticket with code [music] pod30.
Just head to ainativedevcon.io
and we'll see you in London.
Hi there, Simon Maple here and on
today's episode of the AI Native Dev
Podcast, we're here at AI Engineer
London. This is the European event for
AI Engineer. Probably one of the most
premium events here in the AI Engineer
space. So, just take a look at the sheer
number of of sponsors and the quality of
the folks that are going to be here in
the Expo Hall. And the Expo Hall, of
course, is right behind me here. We have
a whole bunch of wonderful people. We're
here to talk to attendees as well as
folks who are here speaking and also on
the Expo floor. We'll hear about what's
new, what's happening in the keynote,
and also what people are here to take
away and learn. Let's go in.
So, joining me is Steve Kaliski, an
engineer at Stripe. Steve, how are you?
>> Good. Thank you for having me.
>> Ah, pleasure. Enjoying AI Engineer so
far?
>> Yeah, I love it. It's really awesome to
just like you're online so much reading
about what's happening, but to actually
see the people here is super cool. So.
>> And what are the people here like,
right? Because this is one of the
premier events
in in the AI engineering space, AI
development space. Um, do you get a
higher class, a higher a higher level
higher levels of adoption of developers,
you know, using AI in their
environments? What kind of conversations
are you having?
>> Yeah, I I think what's interesting is
like
you know, every day like there's a new
announcement about some new models, some
new technology, right? So, everyone here
is like really operating at the leading
edge, right? Everyone here is like
really trying everything the second it
comes out, everything that's new. So,
it's really interesting to sort of like
get the frontier perspective of how
people think about new tools, new
technologies, and so on. So, it's really
exciting.
>> Awesome. So, tell us a little bit about
Stripe and how Stripe is adopting and
using AI in your products.
>> Yeah, sure. So, uh Stripe is using AI in
a few ways, right? So, helping build
Stripe,
helping our customers build their Stripe
integrations, and then also generally
providing, you know, economic tools to
agents and and things like that. So, I
can go off uh through all three quickly.
So, the first one is how we're building
Stripe with AI. So, we have an internal
coding agent called Minions.
>> Okay.
>> And uh you know, sort of like other
coding engines you might have seen but
it's very tuned for Stripe specifically.
>> So it's a model and an agent?
>> Yeah, so we're using you know common
models like
Claude and open AI and so on.
Our harness is forked off of blocks
goose and then we run it internally
within our pre-existing development
environment. So you know maybe I see a
Jira ticket come in or feedback from a
customer I can click a single emoji in
Slack it'll spin up an entire replica of
Stripe
you know as I sort of normally would
have done but it'll now run an agent
loop off of that prompt and then it will
use all of our internal docs and tools
and CI and so on to try to resolve that
prompt.
>> Oh nice.
>> So now we're seeing about 1300 pull
requests
without human assistance
be generated and land per week with the
only intervention is sort of the typical
code review process.
>> So is there still I was going to say is
there still human review?
>> reviewing all the code yes.
>> Yeah yeah do you think they'll get to a
stage where human won't be in the loop
for a bunch of these like lower priority
less critical
>> Yeah so I I I think there are certain
changes where
um
there's not a business logic effect
right? So you can imagine something as
simple as
a typo in the docs
in general might already be something
you'd be comfortable with landing today
already right?
Um so I I assume we'll start that base
case but then increasingly we'll move up
towards
you know features that have a monetary
impact where the sort of risk reward
blend of it landing faster is probably
not in excess of having a human review
it to like double check that it's right.
>> Yeah yeah.
>> So I think there'll be a balance where
some things land you know automatically
in sort of the same way
you know even with GitHub today with
Dependabot doing upgrades and checking
at CI I could probably just let that
land.
>> There are things that would you're
you're happy to accept because it's
lower risk.
>> But then on the flip side like you might
not want that to land right? So the
Axios
and you know all those other kind of
security things that have recently where
you like might not want an automated
package update to go through so it'll
It'd interesting to see how that plays
out, but I don't think anytime soon.
>> Yeah, yeah. And I'd love to hear a
little bit more about your the the
environment that you use there to to to
to build within Stripe. How do you How
important is context as part of that
whole structure?
>> Oh, I mean, it's everything, right? So,
you know, like you know, like the
literal context, like Stripe's been
around for, you know, 10 plus years,
right? There's 10 plus years of context
that doesn't exclusively live in the
code base, right? So, um you know,
any kind of integration with a payment
method or network or um some sort of uh
you know, business logic around how we
treat funds, like that has a legal and
uh compliance and all these other kind
of contextualizations that we try to
manifest in the code base, but also live
in documentation and live in, you know,
our knowledge base and so on and so
forth. So, to be a human engineer at
Stripe, I have to read all that content.
So, if we want our agents to be able to
code effectively, needs to have that
context as well.
>> And how do you manage context? Cuz
obviously there's there's so much of it,
and it's not just, I guess, context
about the code, but also, I guess, your
policies, your ways of working, how you
want code to be to be written, and the
CI/CD process, all that kind of stuff.
How do you How do you manage all of
that? Cuz there must be so much.
>> Yeah, so I I think this is part of one
of the advantages of of us having built
this kind of thing at home, right? Which
is, um
you know,
the engineering you do at Stripe
obviously looks different than the
engineering you do at another company or
at a startup or totally different uh
business domain. So, you know, may-
maybe 80% of coding at Stripe follows
some, you know, uh
blessed paths, right? Maybe I'm making
an API change or change to documentation
or change to introducing a new currency
or so and so forth. And because we can
sort of pattern match to, you know, one
of those pathways, we can make sure that
we're just introducing the appropriate
context to really nail that.
>> Yeah.
>> So, the context you need to make a docs
change looks a lot different than the
context you need to make a cross-border,
you know, uh money transfer kind of
thing, right? So, um
you know, us understanding the type of
product we're building and the type of
changes we're making, lets us, uh, you
know, thoughtfully put in context in
advance. Instead of saying, "Hey, here's
like the entire thing. Good luck." Uh,
which would be impossible for a a normal
person to do that. So.
>> Well, listen, let's wrap up, but I want
to ask you one final question. What is
it you want to learn here at AI Engineer
this week?
>> Yeah, so I I, you know, for me, you
know, obviously there are a lot of
people who are Stripe users, so I'm
excited to talk to them, just to get
feedback so we can make our product
better. But, I also think, you know, to
to that first point, like everyone's
working at the bleeding edge, right? And
it's like impossible to keep up. So,
being able to hear different
perspectives and how people are thinking
about the tools that are coming out, and
how we can best use them, and those
kinds of conversations seems very
useful.
>> Amazing. It's been wonderful chatting,
and I hope you enjoy the rest of AI
Engineer.
>> so much. Appreciate it. Appreciate it.
Thanks.
>> Well, we're lucky enough to chat with
Madison Ford, now one of the speakers at
AI Engineer here in London. Madison,
welcome.
>> Thank you so much. Happy to be here.
>> So, tell us first of all a little bit
about, uh, who you are, what you do, who
you work for.
>> Yeah, so I am an investor. I'm a partner
at NEA, which is, uh, one of the biggest
and oldest VC firms. We do have a London
office, but I am based in San Francisco.
>> Nice.
>> Um, although I do have a lot of
investments in Europe. And I actually
am, uh, former AI researcher. I used to
work at Meta, and led data and AI teams.
So, I have a little bit of a unique
background that more aligns with the
people here versus venture.
Um, so yeah, very excited to be here.
>> Awesome. And what is it you're talking
about here at the conference?
>> Yes, so I am talking about why CI/CD is
dead.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> That's actually the reaction I get from
>> [laughter]
>> Um, but no, it's a really important next
category for us to think about in
agentic software development, because,
um, today everyone's thinking about
agent native engineering. I mean, I
actually have a an investment in that
space that's really exciting called
Factory. They're also speaking here, uh,
this week as well. And when you think
about how engineers are using
traditional CI/CD tools,
those were built for humans pre-cloud,
and you get this massive volume stock in
PRs that we never saw with humans.
Humans were submitting two, maybe three
diffs a week, and now it's just
thousands, maybe tens of thousands, and
you start to get to a place where your
code base is
merging them is just it's impossible.
You can't have so many different agents
taking versions of the same code and
merging them. So, we really needed to be
more inference-native.
>> So, it's almost like is it is it
replacing our existing code base kind of
software?
>> I think that's where we're headed, but I
think right now it doesn't quite look
like that. Right now, I think the best
approach is to have a complimentary
layer where you are speeding up the
build times, development times.
There's a company called Namespace that
I invested in, and we're actually
speaking together on this.
And Namespace helps to speed up your
GitHub action builds, Docker, anything
in that ecosystem so that you don't have
to be sitting there waiting for your
agents to deploy.
But, I do think over time this will
likely replace GitHub and other CICD
tools that are just not built for this
infra.
>> It's interesting as well, because
obviously it's such a it's such an
important part to GitHub's business to
you know GitHub code being such an
important thing and those workplaces.
Going to be very interesting to see how
or if they're even able to change fast
enough to
>> Well, I you know, there's a lot
happening at Microsoft these days. If
someone takes a look, we've been seeing
a lot of reorgs, a lot of leadership
from GitHub is are leaving. Like Thomas
Dohmke. Yes,
and I'm an angel investor in Entain, so
big believer in that.
>> Entain I mean, that's going straight out
and saying we are going to be the new
GitHub.
>> Which Entain really makes sense. I mean,
Microsoft's had the opportunity for a
long time, and they haven't run with it.
So, like why not have a new tool that
actually is built for the cloud, built
for agents,
capturing new code and and creating a
better developer experience.
You know, GitHub has been the the friend
of developers for forever, but it's not
that user-friendly.
>> Yeah.
>> It's not that [laughter] agent-friendly.
>> Specifically with the it's the
agent-friendliness, right? The agent
experience.
>> And then Harness, too, right? Harness,
Circle CI.
I mean, GitLab, like so many of these
tools are just not really scaling to
agent-native software.
>> So, let's go through a bit of your
portfolio. Let's let's Let's hear. What
would you say is the startup that you're
most excited about that people have
never heard about?
>> Okay, love love that.
So, I mean, I have to give a shout-out
to Namespace, but I already talked about
them.
That is probably one that has the least
maybe brand awareness, but so much
developer love.
I mean, Warp is built on top of them.
Sierra, Decagon,
OpenAI is a customer. I mean, they they
have so much love. But, I'll put that
aside. What's the one that has no one
has heard about yet? I would say
probably Golden Analytics. This is
actually super interesting because
Golden is just launched yesterday. It's
a stealth company. And the idea is to
bring the golden era of data and
analytics to builders. So, this is the
first
tool that was truly created to be
end-to-end data autonomy
for everyone versus just the data team.
And they're really trying to blend data
autonomy, as I was mentioning, analytics
and semantic understanding of your data.
But, then the third piece, which I think
is the most compelling, is design and
storytelling. So, how do you actually
ask questions of your data and get full
end-to-end stories where your data is
being You're finding the right data
versus just using the data you have.
So, I think it's going to be a really
big unlock because I'm very bullish on
structured data getting its moment in
the vibe coding era.
>> And that name again, sorry. Go go go go.
>> Golden Analytics.
>> Just launched yesterday. Check it out.
>> Amazing.
>> Really cool product. They have a big
waitlist, so.
>> Yeah, yeah. Excellent. Sounds good. Uh
um
what are you here at AI Engineer to
learn about? What are the things that
you want to unlock?
>> Yeah, so I mean, I I'm always thinking
about as I was mentioning before, kind
of category foresight. Where when you
look forward in 1 to 2 years, does the
existing infrastructure start to crack?
And that's where I want to be
understanding both for my portfolio
companies, um but also for the
enterprise heads of data and heads of
engineering I work very closely with.
Um so I'm looking for where is this not
going to work? Where are things going to
break?
Um who are the thought leaders of that
new era? And I mean, just to get deep
into some of it, I think foundation
models for tabular data are an area I'm
very interested in.
Um
domain-specific foundation models. Um
harnessing engineering I think is
already a huge topic, but just trying to
understand how that sits in the
ecosystem alongside OpenAI and
Anthropic.
Um
so yeah.
>> do you think when talking about those
foundational models, do you think do you
see obviously the billion-dollar
question a while back was around general
models versus specific models?
>> Yes.
>> And we saw companies like Poolside, a
little bit quieter these days, but
Poolside they you know, they were
created they were they were putting huge
investment in this massive massive uh
amounts of money that they were valued
at.
Do you see that now as the unlock,
particularly with my awesome things like
that being announced as like killer
models which have been trained very
specifically? Do you see general models
fading away for specific models?
>> I think general models will always be
very helpful for orchestration and
routing to other models. And maybe that
looks like mixture of experts where
there is certain expertise on small
models. That's actually a part of my bet
with the tabular data space. For For I
think data's a really good example of
one where foundation models will not be
able to come in and build precise
structured data, but the tabular data
architecture might be one that a large
language model is able to route to.
So overall, I'm actually very bullish on
small specialized models for different
domains.
I don't think coding is necessarily one
that will be in that, you know,
specialized domain, but I do think
there's a big opportunity for harness
engineering there. Some of the more
specialized areas I'm excited about are
material science, not possible with a
large language model.
We have a company called Cuspaider, it's
actually based in London.
So
sovereignty and
language specific models, so like
reflection in the US, Sakana in Japan,
Mistral in Europe, I think are very
interesting. Um
And then we have another one that's
foundation model for CAD, so think about
mechanical engineering and product
design. Very difficult problem. This is
not something you can just release
a, you know, large language model or
even a coding model to do,
but it's very precise for that use case
that's built for the multi-modality.
So I definitely think there are huge
markets that haven't even been touched
by AI yet with small specialized models.
We're being very thoughtful about
betting in a lot of those categories
right now.
>> It's been wonderful chatting with you,
Madison, and enjoy the rest of AI
Engineer and good luck with the session.
>> Thank you.
>> We're here with Omar Sanseverino, who is
the developer experience lead at Google
DeepMind.
Sounds amazing. Tell us a little bit
about what the role is and what you do
at Google.
>> Yeah, of course. So I lead all of the
model launches at DeepMind, so Nano,
Banana, Bio, Gemini, and of course
Gemma. So last week we released Gemma 4,
which is the latest addition to the open
model family of models.
So yeah.
>> Amazing. And tell us a little bit about
what each model is trying to address.
What's the Why would someone use one of
those specific models?
>> Yeah, of course. So, uh so there are
models that are for Gen Media. So, we
just released Lyra as well for music
generation. We have VEO for video
generation, Nano Banana, which is pretty
much for image um
editing and image generation. And then
we have Gemini like the core famous
Gemini model, which is a flagship model
if you want the best capabilities, the
most knowledge, all of these gigantic,
high-performance coding capabilities.
And we have Gemma, which is as I was
mentioning like
the open models that we have released.
Last week we did Gemma 4, which is the
most capable model that can fit in a
consumer GPU. That means that these are
models that you can run in your own
devices. And that can mean your own
desktop computer, your own laptop, and
even the smallest Gemma models can run
in your own phone.
So, trying to pack as much intelligence
per parameter as we can.
>> Amazing. So, so the one the key feature
of Gemma is its size.
>> It's its size and also the control that
it provides you. So, you can run these
models in your own hardware. And you can
even do something called fine-tuning,
which means that you can modify the
models for your own use cases. So, let's
say that you're working in a setup where
the information has a data type that is
very tricky like legal setups or maybe
like a specific medical type of data
that must proprietary models have never
seen before. So, you can pick Gemma and
you can modify it for your own use case.
And it and it can work quite well. And
then you can serve that model in your
own infrastructure and your own devices.
>> Amazing. So, you did a launch just
recently. Did you say yesterday or this
week?
>> Last week.
>> Last week. Last week.
>> So, last week on Thursday, so that was 6
days ago. And now we have over 10
million downloads already. Yeah, yeah.
And over 1,000 Gemma 4-based models
built by the community, which
>> I suppose you had launch partners and
things like that. What what what are
people starting to do with Gemma
already?
>> Yeah, so what is critical for us is that
when we release new models, people can
use the models with whichever are their
favorite tools, right? So, we
collaborate with Ollama, with Hugging
Face, with Unsloth, with Llama.cpp. So,
pretty much no matter which is their
tool, people should be able to
experiment with the Gemma models. And
it's the same strategy for Gemini. We
work with LangChain, Llama index, and so
on. And people are building very
exciting things. So, people are running
the models in their phone, they are
doing even agentic stuff within the
phone. So, as part of the launch we did
an application called the Google AI Edge
Gallery. You can install that in iOS,
you can install that install it in
Android as well. And it allows you to do
things such as adding new skills, even
like controlling your phone, like
turning on the flashlight and doing like
different UI
device control things, which is quite
exciting.
>> Interesting, interesting. I'd love to
lean the conversation more into context
now as well, which we see
it feels like context always opens
models up in terms of getting the to get
the best out of models, you need to
almost like customize in context and
skills and things like that. Seem like a
really good way to provide that
information about how to customize your
usage. With the different models that
you just mentioned, would you say
context is as important with with
various models or would you say there
are specific use cases where it's it's
so important and others where it's less
important?
>> Yeah, yeah, that's a great question. So,
let's talk about Gemini and Gemma. Of
course, Gemini has a much longer context
window. You can pass videos of 1 hour,
you can pass very long documents. In the
context of Gemma, these are small models
designed to run on device. And the issue
is that the context does consume your
GPU, so you cannot just provide like a
huge context without having to burn much
more compute, right? So, for us that
that part is quite important. So, the
smallest Gemma models support context of
about 220K. The larger Gemma models
support 256K, which is nice for on
device, but it's still like much shorter
than what you could try with Gemini.
>> So, the context curation is actually far
more important to actually
>> important
>> make sure the context is small enough
for the model to actually use correctly.
>> And the other part is also thinking
efficiency, right? So, there are
different open models and how many
tokens or how much thinking or reasoning
the model needs to do to get to an
answer can vary per model. So, that's
something that we also look quite a bit.
So, making sure that when models are
reasoning, they don't generate like just
like a super long chain of thought,
right? And that they can actually
generate like a dense like highly useful
highly like dense kind of information in
the context.
>> Yeah, yeah. So, we're at AI Engineer
here in London. Great to be here. What
are the things you want to take away
from the conference?
>> Yeah, so the first part is to just meet
with the ecosystem like all of as I was
saying like for us it's critical to have
ecosystem partners to collaborate with
them to contribute to the open source
ecosystem. So, it's great to meet with
all of them in person. And then the
other part is just like listening to all
of these exciting use cases like what
people are building.
The last time I was at AI Engineer
conference was 1 year ago in New York.
>> In Paris or is it Paris? Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
>> Yeah, in New York. New York. It was a
yeah, in the winter of last year.
Just in the last year so much has
changed, right? Like it's so exciting
now to see like what people are building
even like compared to 6 months ago or a
few months ago. So, now I want to see
where we're standing 6 months from now,
right? It would be quite exciting.
>> Well, there's a lot of exciting things
coming out of Google Gemini as well and
very very keen to hear what's coming and
what's what's what's going to be in the
future.
>> Yeah, yeah. For us what is critical is
to also like build based on the feedback
from the community. So, pretty much for
Gemma 4 for example, we
we gather all of this feedback from the
last year. So, people were for example
asking for function calling and agent
capabilities, a better license. So, we
changed our license to be Apache 2
actually as well.
So, pretty much this is a kind of
opportunities also to gather as much
feedback what we're doing right but what
we're doing wrong, right? And how we can
iterate and we're executing as a startup
as much as we can. So, trying to release
models, release new capabilities,
release new tools as quickly as possible
to get feedback and iterate based on
that.
>> Amazing. I'm actually having a wonderful
chat and enjoy the rest of AI Engineer.
>> Yeah, thank you so much for having me
here.
>> Cheers.
Now, I'm here by the 11 Labs phone booth
and I'm going to go in and try it out.
It's going to basically going to ask me
a number of questions about British AI.
Let's see how I do.
>> What classic party
That was Oh,
uh 2016. Was it chess?
We're back here at the Eleven Labs booth
and joining me Boris Starling, who is a
growth engineer uh at at Eleven Labs.
What is a What is a growth engineer?
>> Well, uh growth engineer is a little bit
of everything, little bit of marketing,
of engineering, and a little bit of fun
projects like a booth.
>> that booth that booth was the you were
the creator of that. You built You built
under the covers. Tell me a little bit
about the technology behind that.
>> So, the hardest part was actually
reverse engineering the actual phone. We
used cloud codes to reverse engineer the
low-level protocol of it, and uh then we
connected it to Twilio, and uh
connected Twilio to Eleven Labs agents.
And that's how it works.
>> That sounds cool. And it really was a
phone line. You would You were actually
calling uh uh
made a connection, and then you were
there was an agent at the end that was
that was answering back. It really was
Michael Caine, right?
>> It is. It is. We have
>> [laughter]
>> the license his voice.
>> Amazing. Yeah. Cool. Cool. So, tell us a
little bit about Eleven Labs, what
Eleven Labs does.
>> Well, uh we started as a text-to-speech
company. Right now, we do everything. We
have a AI agents platform. We have a
creative platform with a bunch of uh
tools for creators.
Um and um yeah, we do we do a little bit
of everything now. We even have a music
product now.
>> Oh, amazing. And actually, one of the
things that I I heard Mati uh who Mati
who's on the who's on the uh podcast, uh
co-founder of Eleven Labs, uh one of the
things that he said was
uh voice will be the way that
developers, engineers will engage with
AI. How much do you use Eleven Labs
internally during your development and
during your engineering?
>> Yeah, this is a fun one. Actually, we
we've built a tool internally to use the
voice with Cloud Code before Cloud Code
actually integrated the voice into their
product. And uh we also have a tool
again like internally
um to use voice with Open Flow, so that
Open Flow can call you and you can call
it and it's like
truly conversational.
>> Yeah. Amazing. Amazing. And what's new
in in Eleven Labs these days?
>> What's new? Well, we're growing really
fast. It's uh we have a hundred
>> a round as well recently as well, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. We recently raised a new
round of eleven billion valuation.
>> Wow.
>> So
>> Yeah. Congratulations. Awesome. So what
are the some what are the some of the
conversations you're having with uh
people at AI Engineer today? Are you Are
people mostly using Eleven Labs
interested in kind of like integrating
voice into their product or development?
>> Yeah, people are very curious about the
both. They use it as an entry point to
show the what the agents, the Eleven
Labs agents, are capable of. So usually
people come go through the quiz and then
I show them the actual agent that they
spoke to and I can I I can even show
them the actual conversation that
>> Oh, wow. Amazing. Amazing. Uh Boris,
it's been great chatting. Uh I hope you
enjoy the rest of AI Engineer.
>> Thank you, Simon.
>> No problem.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Cheers.
Awesome. And we're here just next to the
Open AI booth and we have uh Ryan
LeCompte who is a member of technical
staff at Open AI joining us. So Ryan,
welcome.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> Is this your first AI Engineer or you've
been to plenty in the past?
>> my first one.
>> This is your first one.
>> Yeah, excited to be here in London. It's
been a It's been a great crowd.
>> And uh where are you based normally?
>> Uh Seattle.
>> Seattle. Oh, okay. So it's a bit of a
trip bit of a trip for you.
Um so uh Ryan, first of all uh what are
you talking on here today?
>> Uh talking about harness engineering and
sort of the arc of implementation that
my team and I have been on over the last
nine months to remove ourselves from the
process of writing code as much as
possible. I kind of have like banned my
team from opening their editor and it's
been wild to see how quickly we've been
able to stack capability into the code
base to let agents do more and more of
the software job.
>> And that's really interesting cuz you'll
get you'll get different types of
developers. Some who like that scares
them completely. Like I don't My god,
that's my that's my happy place, you
know, in an IDE writing code. But
realistically, I think there's going to
be different types of developers. Those
that who are creators that will
absolutely love this because the the the
the job of writing code can be happen
faster and it can get taken away from
them and they can create faster. What's
your reaction to
or or I guess what's your team's
reaction to whipping out the IDE from
underneath them?
>> I am a a Rubius. Ruby was my first love,
so metaprogramming is kind of a thing
that is like in my bones, right? I want
to kind of lift myself up a level, use
high-level extractions to kind of do the
job for me. And I do feel like the
harness engineering is really similar to
this, right? I am working through a
super high-level primitive in a coding
agent to do the code production itself.
So, the levers I have around me are
different. Uh it's all around refining
output rather than generating it
directly myself.
>> Right.
>> A trick that I have used though is to
just My team is all external hires and
they just go full yolo insane into this
thing. This is the way we do it. This is
why we're at a frontier lab to invent
the future.
>> Amazing. So, talk us through some of the
some of the principles of harness
engineering then.
>> Fundamentally, the models are limited on
two things: attention and context. In
order to maximize attention and limit
context, we want
the code, the process, the test to be
the same as much as possible, and we
want the agents to largely cook with the
minimum amount of instructions, giving
it context just in time in order to
efficiently respect that context and let
it operate over very long time horizons.
Instead of front-loading all the context
into agents.md, I want to just-in-time
inject how to remediate a linter failure
at the time it happens. And this allows
us to have like much wider periods of
black box behavior where the agent is
reasoning and cooking and writing code
and resolving its own failures, which
allows me to kind of look at the
beginning and the end of a task rather
than the messy middle sort of thing.
>> Yeah, interesting. And And so, how is
that done then? Is that done through
skills and things like that? Some Some
of that almost like progressive
disclosure of context into the agent?
>> That's right. That's right. Uh we use
skills for this. We actually uh have
very few skills in the code base that we
want to centralize around. I think we
have five or six. All the engineers on
the team contribute to those. And this
way we can kind of optimize the human
involvement in the process to not have
to change too much. We have a fixed
number of entry points into the model.
Uh and then it's all about figuring
creative ways to inject prompts into
context, right? Those skills are
prompts. Error messages from tests are
prompts. Review feedback, which comes
mostly from agents, also are prompts. Uh
and it's all about getting them
just-in-time injected and making sure
that they are somewhat reliably
followed, right? Like the models create
text, we need to figure out ways to give
them text.
>> So, in order for this to be successful,
does it reflect that it's all about the
skills being accurately written
accurately crafted so that the so that
the agents are are are essentially
guided in the right way? Otherwise,
they're never going to get to that end
point.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. This is why uh I don't
really use plan mode very often because
>> I'm hearing that more and more actually.
It's surprising, right?
>> these big plans that I like really don't
want to review and I hit yes to accept
them. But if those plans actually encode
instructions that are wrong, like I'm
pushing the agent in the wrong
direction.
>> we learn as we go that will actually
affect how we've done that original
planning.
>> Yes.
>> Very interesting.
>> Well, the the time I want to spend is on
like the most ambiguous, hardest work
over the course of building a product,
right? And I don't necessarily know the
right shape at the beginning. And the
agents operate the same way when they're
writing code for a PR. We want them to
kind of figure it out as they go to kind
of go from a lot of white space in front
of them to a nice refined high quality
output.
>> Yeah.
>> And getting feedback along the way is a
big part of that.
>> Amazing. Now, you're also going to be
talking about exactly this topic at AI
and Native DevCon, which is happening
June 1st and 2nd right here in London.
>> Super jazzed about that.
>> Which is what? Like less than 2 months
away now, so not too not too far away.
Um what what is your what is the
reaction
to to to this session though? You know,
when when you present this session, do
you are developers typically on board
with it? Are they a little bit hesitant
with it?
>> Uh
I get a mix, right? Folks
don't want to move their hands from the
keyboard, right? Like there's this fear
that the code is going to be misaligned,
right? And this maybe feeling that it's
going to provide me with more work to
clean up the mess afterward. But
if you invest your time instead to just
simply saying I will not accept slop, I
don't let the agents produce slop, and I
systematize the reduction of slop, you
have kind of
accomplished the same goal with much
fewer synchronous attention cycles from
yourself. You want to kind of think like
a staff engineer, and you have five or
50 engineers at your disposal. And with
that amount of resources, there's a lot
of damage you can do in sort of reducing
bad code from being produced.
>> Yeah.
>> Rather than having to shoulder surf
along the way.
>> Yeah. So, let's talk a little bit about
your environment. In terms of when
you're doing harness engineering, what
does your environment look like?
Presumably you're using Codex?
>> Yes, using Codex.
>> Uh I'm hearing on on Twitter, by the
way. I'm hearing so many people go like,
"Oh my god, Code Codex is just like
unlocking me." And it's like I see so
many people jumping into Codex right
now. It's it's very interesting to see.
>> Codex does the full job. Like I can
trust it to go from prompt to merge PR
with high quality code reproductions of
the work that it has done in the same
way I would expect a human, right? Like
when I'm working on back-end systems,
right? I'm supposed to deploy it to
staging.
My teammates don't like come over to my
computer and like look at my command
history to see that I deployed to
staging. I'm making an attestation in
the PR with some proof that shows that I
did this, and they largely accept it as
true. And Codex is able to operate in
the same way, which gives me high
confidence that it's able to do the job.
I see it executing for 6, 12, 30 hours
at this insane pace on Twitter where the
laptop is buckled into the back seat of
my car.
>> [laughter]
>> Burning tokens as I'm coming to and from
work because it is able to do these very
complex changes. And the way we do that
is Chewie, the web product, the app,
which is super super awesome. I love the
automations in it. It's constantly
cleaning up after itself, you know,
every hour making sure my CI is green,
making sure that like, you know, we have
adhere to our golden principles around
what good looks like.
>> I have a sticker on my laptop and it
says AI codes while I sleep. AI works
while I sleep. We're in that space now.
capable enough now that that we can do
that. Um, we're at AI Engineering as I
mentioned. What is the What is the one
thing you want to learn from the AI
Engineering conference? Is it chatting
to people? Is it What's What's What's
What's the thing you want to take away?
>> The thing I want to learn is where folks
are at with these tools. What will it
take them to 10x the level of trust and
usage of the model to enable them to
build more and more
products for the world to like solve
more and more user problems, right? Like
so much software is yet to be produced
that like we now have the option to do
because implementation is so cheap.
So, talking with folks, figuring out
where it is they get hung up and how we
can bring that to the product is
something that I'm super super excited
about.
>> Amazing. Right, it's been wonderful
chatting with you, and I totally look
forward to your session at AI Native
DevCon, June 1st 2nd in London as well.
So,
>> I'll be there.
>> Excellent. Thanks very much.
Hey everyone. Hope you're enjoying the
episode so far.
>> [music]
>> Our team is working really hard behind
the scenes to bring you the best guests
so we can have the most informative
conversations about agentic development.
Whether that's talking about the latest
tools, the most efficient workflows, or
defining best practices. But, for
whatever reason, many of you have yet to
subscribe to the channel. If you're
enjoying the podcast and want us to
continue to bring you the very best
content, please do us a favor and hit
that subscribe button. It [music] really
does make a difference and lets us
continue to improve the quality of our
guests and build an even better product
for you. All right, back to the episode.
>> Well, we're here still in the in the
expo hall at AI engineer and we've we've
bumped into Jordan Jerrett who is a an
applied AI team lead for the incubator
for artificial intelligence project
for the government. So, tell us a little
bit about your role and what you do.
>> Very good to see you. Yeah, so as you
said, I'm the applied AI team lead in
the incubator for AI. We're a team of
about 50 technical whole permanent civil
servants working in UK government to
prove that AI can be used as a tool for
the public good.
>> Amazing. And so, tell us tell us tell us
a little bit about kind of you know, how
the government is using AI today.
>> Yeah, so there's a lot going on in a lot
of different places.
But, what we think there's a real need
for in government is to have really
strong technical capability and like a
full-fledged product development applied
AI team that can ship things from zero
to one and like get things and scale
them out across the public sector.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so, three things that we're working
on at the moment which we think are
really really exciting. First of which
is government consultations. We built
the default app for
analyzing government consultations
that's saving hundreds of thousands of
hours a year and many many millions of
pounds and is also more quantitative and
better than humans analyzing these
consultations.
>> Okay.
>> Rolling that out to look at
consultations like digital ID and other
sort of ongoing things that are big
contentious political issues.
>> And for those who aren't in the UK
recognizing UK government, what is a
consultation?
>> Consultation is when government goes out
and asks the public what their views are
on a major piece of like legislation,
how it's going to affect what you can
and can't do in the UK. So, it's a
really important part of the democratic
process. And getting that analysis right
is really important. Yeah. One of the
things we really have to be able to
prove with our AI models is that humans
agree
with our AI consultation analysis tool
more than they agree with each other.
>> Right.
>> As a result of it. The um second thing
that we're doing is digitizing the
planning system.
>> This is This is super interesting. You
showed me this earlier.
>> Take a look.
>> So, so tell us a little bit about
Well, tell us a little bit about Tell us
about the problems, I guess, that exist
in in that space today and how AI
>> Come and get a look at this. This is one
of the basements of a council in the UK.
And
what you can see here are boxes and
boxes full of old planning records,
which tell you what you can and can't do
with the land in the UK.
>> This is stressing me out. This is really
stressing me out.
>> I've had people say, "I hope that the
basement floods so that all these
records get destroyed and we don't have
to go down and look at them every time
you apply for a let's say an extension
on your house or getting a new asset."
>> So, planning permission a planning
permission application comes in. Someone
physically has to go down. They have to
try and identify a card from from the
from these places, pull it out, read
what it is, and then understand, "Okay,
yes, you do have these permissions." or
"No, this this this tree has a
conservation order on it." or whatever
those issues are. It's a very, very
manual process.
>> Very manual and we've got
what is often a very paper-based system.
So,
>> This isn't an AI problem. This is a data
problem, as you mentioned earlier. So,
what are the What are the stages that
need to go through in order to
digitalize this? And then how does AI
help?
>> Cool. So, what we're doing is we're
taking these nasty old documents
and we've created multimodal agents that
can go and take them and turn them into
nice
geospatial data. So, this is a little
like a demo of of of our app here. You
You see you can get our local planning
officer can go and upload that PDF. We
use models like Flooding like
Gemini to go through and do structured
information extraction. Then do a lot of
extra hard work on top of it to go and
figure out where in the country this map
is, what the correct objects on that map
are, and segment them, and then figure
out the coordinate transforms from this
old pixel coordinate map to this modern
geospatial data. You can then see here
we're also working with the planning
officers to get them to go and tweak and
edit it and correct that one will enable
them to go and upload their data to
the um
the the planning portal,
planning.data.gov.
So we start to fill in this map of what
you can do with the land in the UK.
Um the other thing is we also get to
keep all that data for our e-vals. We
can create a self-improving system so we
can digitize the system even faster.
>> The e-vals are so so important for that.
>> So crucial. We showed it to the PM and
he committed to digitize the UK's
planning system by the end of the year.
So
what we're doing is trying to prove that
AI can be used as a tool for the public
good.
>> Yeah.
>> And be like pretty radical about the
things that we try and achieve with it.
>> And when you say by the end of the year,
what scale of data are we talking about
here?
>> I want to see that map filled in.
>> And and and what what does that mean in
terms of like this sheer number of of
the volume of documents and things like
that?
>> So we did hundreds of thousands of
documents at least
and millions and millions of trees and
old like fields and lots of different
the whole history a whole stack of
different like land use that we need to
go through and digitize.
>> And from a productivity point of view
like if we think about a human doing
this this Still a human in the loop as
we as we mentioned but
a human doing this like what kind of a
productivity improvement are we talking
about?
>> So it often takes a planning officer
about an hour to digitize one of these
records properly. They also don't
necessarily always fill in the
information in exactly the right way.
Now we can get it done in about a minute
two minutes for about 10 p.
>> Yeah.
>> So there's another problem which is
there aren't enough
planning officers in the UK to be able
to do this. Yeah, Hey, we need to kind
of like think about how we can use AI to
transform like the labor market problem
here.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so there's this thing and then you
then you can ask so that that's one
layer of efficiency. That's that's
that's kind of like one useful thing to
do. We save time, we save money.
But think about what we can do on top of
this, right? So like once we have a
digital planning system, what can you
do? Well, you can start to
do things like this
>> Yeah.
>> which is build agents on top of that
like digital planning stack. So you
could say create an assistant for our
planning officer. So when you put in
your application, the agent can go run,
draw down all of the evidence that it
needs, suggest the right decision, and
get instead of an answer in 13 weeks,
get an answer in a week.
>> Yeah.
>> Like that's the sort of future we want
to enable through digitizing the
planning system.
Um
and there's a ton of all like brilliant
prop tech companies in the UK that are
also pretty desperate to get their hands
on this information as well. So
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> we think there's a role for AI to be
used to be able to curate and then
publish more open data in the UK for
people to build on.
>> Amazing. Um
I feel like the government the UK
government is actually very very
progressive with a lot of the digital
assets that it's done over the over the
last 10 20 years even. In terms of like
the AI usage, are there like a number of
restrictions based on the sensitivity of
the data, there's there's certain models
you can't use or or things you need to
be extra careful about here?
>> So in the incubator for AI, we're
fortunate in that we're given quite a
lot of trust and quite a lot of control
over our own stack. So we're a team like
of developers, we're very like
engineering first in what we do. So we
are able to use pretty much whatever we
want. We've got a lot of funding to be
able to go and like play around with
these models. Um I'll also mention we're
hiring for a load of applied AI
engineers. So if anyone should come and
join us on that that mission at the
moment, they definitely should get in
touch.
>> Where's the best place to get in touch?
>> They can go to ai.gov.uk.
>> Yep.
>> Um and there's a careers page there they
can check out. Um
and um yeah, but like we also have to
think about how we kind of deploy these
tools responsibly and
>> and safely. Um
and
and that's a big part of the work is
evaluating, like, really, really
carefully the quality of the output of
our models. So, we're we're both applied
AI engineers who want to build stuff,
but we also want to
really, like, rigorously test our own
work. Prove that it's good. One way that
we're doing that, if I can shoehorn it
in, is the work we're doing in
education. Um,
so there's
for the last sort of 6 months, um,
the Department for Education has really
had its fingers in the in its ears about
the use of AI in education. And kids are
already using AI as a tutor.
>> Yes.
>> But we don't know whether that's safe or
effective. We don't know if that's a
good way to learn.
And as government, we've got a
responsibility to make sure that people
are learning well. So, what we're doing
about it, um,
we're constructing a first-of-its-kind
benchmark for AI tutoring. And that
involves a lot of things, but primarily
that's working with teachers, EdTech
market, um, and the Department for
Education to define what good pedagogy
looks like. So, are you giving the right
sort of advice to children? Are you
doing that in a way that's conducive to
them learning? You're not just feeding
them the answers, but you're teaching
them how to learn.
And also, um, doing it in a way that's
safe. So, if you're creating dependence,
for instance, or creating like an
emotional attachment, can you like
prevent it from doing that? So, coming
up with a wider range of, like, uh,
metrics that we can use to analyze these
long-form student-teacher interactions
over here. Um, we're then also working
with the Frontier Labs to turn these
into benchmarks that they can go and
test their models against to see, before
these things get into the classrooms,
whether they're safe or effective.
>> Excellent. Amazing. And it's so
wonderful to see
like, AI being applied in such a in such
a in such a way that is actually, like
you said, for the good, for public good.
So,
thank you so, so much for sharing.
Really, really, uh, really, really great
to hear. Uh, one last question before we
go.
We're at AI Engineer. What are you
hoping to learn
or or share with the audience?
>> Cool. So,
first thing I'm wanting to share is
basically the vision. I want to I want
people to know that they can come into
government for a tour of duty, come and
work with us for a bit, do some of the
most like impactful work of their
career, affect everyone in the country
in the process. And there's a place for
you to do it, which is Incubator for AI.
Um they should also check out the number
10 Innovation Fellowship Program, which
is for like the top tier technical
talent to come into government on a tour
of duty, too. Really exciting
opportunity.
>> that you're a a member of as well.
>> Yeah, yeah. So, that's how I got into
government. I was in academia doing like
some computational bioengineering stuff,
like in deep biotech. I thought I want
to work on stuff with massive social
impact. And I find it really gratifying.
I've chosen to stay. Um
the other thing I'm really excited about
in the conference here is just the
quality of the people in the room. It's
like the most incredible crowd. Um huge
credit to like Shawn and the organizers
for for pulling this off.
I've I've had this thing in the back of
my mind, which is like what does the
government agent stack look like?
>> Yeah.
>> We've got this like really gnarly sort
of tech setup in the UK, where you've
got lots of delegated kind of um
different sort of cloud environments
with different responsibilities,
but
it doesn't really reflect how people
think about what government is. They
think of government as one organization,
but we don't operate like that.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I'm thinking like
how could I work with something like
Work OS um or some of the other kind of
like um
uh sort of deployment and like infra
platforms that we've got can see in the
room here to build agents that could
work seamlessly across government.
>> Yeah.
>> And you have any You give me any
pointers on that? I'd be very grateful.
>> Yeah, that's really good. Yeah, yeah.
Awesome. Thanks so so much. Been great
chatting with you and enjoy the rest of
your night today.
>> Yeah, cheers.
>> Cheers.
Look who I bumped into, Nipa, who we
actually yesterday had a panel at the
Tess office for the AI and Native Dev
community. So, it's great to see you
here at AI Engineer. How are you?
>> I'm good. Thanks for inviting me.
Yesterday was a really nice session.
>> It was amazing. And of course, you're a
solutions engineer at Cado. Tell us a
little bit about Cado, what you do, and
and and what you do at Coda, and what
Coda does as well.
>> Yeah. I'm a solution engineer with Coda,
so try to solve problems that AI creates
by AI.
So, it's like a loop. AI creates
problem, and AI is trying to resolve
>> right?
>> Exactly. So, at Coda, what we are trying
to solve is the code. So, when you use
AI, you create so much amount of code
that it practically becomes impossible
to keep track on what exactly is being
created, is that a the standards can be
actually promoted to production.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
initially and currently as well, we see
every now and
and then
things, security concerns coming up in
the production with major
players as well. So, we are trying to
make sure we can reduce those gaps as
much as we can by providing guardrails,
by providing more patterns for the
organizations work with, so that the
secure code can be promoted to the
production.
>> Now, when I first heard about Coda, it
was Codium back in the day, and then it
moved over, and and Codium
was built around testing.
>> Yes.
>> Um and essentially creating unit tests,
those types of things, and then
rebranded to Coda. Much much more about
it, feels like it's much much more about
code reviews these days. Is that Is that
>> That's true. That's true. So, when we
started 3 years back, we started with
code gen, we started with testing a part
of code reviews. But as we grew, we
understand before even testing can come
into picture, code reviews is a step
where we have a major gap. And that's
where the whole team thought like,
"Okay, let's try to fill in that gap,
and we are good at it."
For example, for the last years, we are
just trying to make sure we don't do
only code reviews, we reduce the noise,
which usually nobody is looking at. If
you see the code gen as well, it's more
the better. But what we are saying is
it's not more the better, it's more
about more quality, the better it is.
So, we shifted all our focus to code
reviews and then now we do good reviews.
>> So, there's two important things I think
about code reviews. One is with the with
agentic development,
we obviously need
possibly a human in the loop, possibly
some deterministic testing to say is
this code reasonable of reasonable
quality? The second thing is the sheer
volume of code that is being delivered
these days and that will be delivered in
future. I think Logan Kilpatrick kind of
from Google DeepMind said he's expecting
5 years a million times more code that
we generate than today.
With that volume, how do we how
important is code review to enable that
we deliver at speed while maintaining
that we're not just shipping rubbish
into production?
>> Sure. I think that's the main focus of
current code review industry. It's I
think this is a problem not only us,
anybody in this industry is trying to
solve because again, everybody thought
process is we have to ship faster, we
have to develop more. But at what cost?
Do you want to ship faster in a week and
spend
maybe 2 weeks trying to figure out what
went wrong and how to fix it? Or do you
want to make sure you can ship faster
with guardrails, with making sure the
code you are providing to the
production is good enough. So, I think
we should be a balance where it's not
about shipping faster, but it's finding
a balance where you can ship faster with
the quality code in production.
>> And what's more important would you say
cuz I like the industry, there are
startups flying out everywhere.
Everyone's Everyone's going fast. Would
you say it's more important to have high
speed or would you say it's more
important to have like zero issues?
Because of course, if we can react to
know to to known issues that we that we
ship, is that better or worse than
shipping perfect code, but it taking
longer?
>> Uh yeah, I think in the previous days as
well, there were senior developers who
can actually build their code in a
couple of weeks and then ship it. And
now as well with the AI, it's the
faster. I think it should not be very
restricted, otherwise we are restricting
the tech or the thing which we are
working towards. But we should
differentiate between what is critical
and what not. Why not experiment with
going faster, creating more experimental
guardrails on the things which are least
important, but still
making sure the critical work we are
doing around can be saved and can be
checked a little bit more better. And I
think we are in a place where we we are
becoming more and more comfortable with
AI doing a lot of automation. So yeah,
we can experiment with the non-critical
stuff, and once we are comfortable,
maybe try it with so we should find a
balance not restricting because then the
whole point of
getting AI and shipping more code goes
away.
>> Yeah.
>> But on the other hand, not let
everything done be by AI so that it you
have to pay a lot of cost for that.
Yeah.
>> How do you advise developers use context
and skills to create
you know,
better, higher quality code from scratch
that then obviously we still need to
validate and test against, but really
getting that baseline to be better. How
would you How would you encourage people
to use like skills and context to to to
really enable their agents?
>> Yeah, when you say context, context is
crazy nowadays, and this question is
crazy too.
>> [laughter]
>> Because if you see the context, people
don't understand what the context means
for them. When you say a developer,
okay, the context is important, they
think, okay, everything what I have in
the organization, the whole code base,
you know, the Confluence documents, the
Jira documents. Although the context
window for our AI models is increasing
day by day, but does it actually impact
or does it understand the whole context?
You can dump the whole code base to the
LLMs. Does it understand? Does
it actually look into things and say
this is important or not? And if you see
the current, we are not into that.
You can dump data on to data, but LLMs
cannot. They just choose the first part
and the last part and all in between
context is lost.
>> It's about the right context, the right
skills, the right context.
>> Exactly. And then the second part is the
mature developers thinks like they can
build context engine. They can create
whole vector DB or the mapping, but is
that really important? Is that really
worth spending the time on? So, for me
it's important to understand what
exactly I'm trying to target, what kind
of problem I'm trying to achieve and
based upon that choose what's important,
what kind of context mapping I can do
instead of building a whole context
engine. Can I do iterative reduction or
can I do hierarchical mapping? And then
create something to make your results
better.
>> And let's wrap up with a final question.
What do you want to learn? What What do
you want to take away from the AI
engineering conference?
>> Oh, I think the
the conversations I have is the most
important key for me this conference
because when you look when you work with
a product or when you work with a
specific organization, you tend to start
looking in a specific way. If you see
AI, it's being
used in so many different ways, so many
use cases. Talking with people gives you
an idea what exactly is happening, what
are the problems. And next time maybe
I'm solving a problem, I have that I'm a
solution architect. That's what I do,
right?
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> So, it gives me a new idea about what
actual problems are and how can I help.
>> Amazing. But it's been awesome to talk
with you again and enjoy the rest of AI
engineering.
>> Thank you, Lonnie. You're so great.
>> Thank you.
So, we're on the the Zed booth and
joining me is Cameron McLaughlin, an
engineer at Zed. Cameron, how are you
doing?
>> Pretty good. It's been a happy to be
here, very excited.
>> Were you here last night as well?
>> Yeah, last night setting up and meeting
a few people, checking out the other
booths.
>> So, tell me like Zed is an amazing IDE.
We've had a couple of people at Tesla
play at play with it and and and use it
a little bit as well. Um, tell us a
little bit about what Zed is and also
what's happening in the world of Zed.
>> Well, it's a text editor. It's a a
generic coding tool. It's, you know,
it's a review tool, I guess, if you want
it to be. It's kind of, you know, it's
it's what you expect from a text editor
and IDE.
It's Why why should you use Zed? I mean,
I like it cuz it's really fast. It's uh
it's not on a browser. It's like an all
Electron app. It's just written in Rust
from the ground up. We have our own UI
framework, our own, you know, our own
everything. We built it all from
scratch. Um
>> What's the reason that someone would use
Zed compared to a Cursor or something
like that?
>> It's It's a lot faster. That's That's
something that really affects me, like,
you know, I you know, I've used Cursor
for a bit and you know, sometimes you
press a key and it you know, there's a
little delay and you use Zed and you
press a key and it's the next frame
every time without fail. Uh that's
something that's really important to me.
I think also, like, we So, we just
launched our parallel agents feature.
Oh, wait, our our demo's not up, but we
have this we have this new sidebar. You
can run agents in parallel. You can have
all of them going. You can use ACP, so
you can have Zed agent or you can have
Clock Code, Codex, any of these open
code, whatever you want.
>> You know, Zed was actually one of the
first uh kind of like truly use ACP,
right? I
>> Oh, we created it.
>> [laughter]
>> It's sort of I I'm not That makes so
much sense now.
Um Well, cuz I think, like, you know, it
you know, we all remember the world
before LSP and like how, you know, every
editor had to make their own Java
extension like C extension and all of
this stuff and then LSP was pretty
revolutionary in allowing lots of
editors to sort of speak the same
language and I think it's obvious that
to at least it's obvious to us that we
need a similar protocol for agents. Um
you know, you can enjoy one harness and
not particularly like its its UI or you
just don't want to keep switching key
bindings, you know, you don't have to
like shift enter to send a message or
just enter in another one, you know, all
all of these things. They like the the
friction adds up over time and this
there's something that I've really come
to appreciate with Zed is like it's very
optimized for like low friction.
>> Yeah.
>> It's, you know, everything's fast.
Everything's how you're used to it.
The other thing I really appreciate is
the collaboration features. We don't
have the demo set up at the moment, but
the
um
it's a bit like a Slack huddle. You can
sort of join a huddle, pair with your
teammates, you can talk to them. Within
Zed, yeah. So, there's like built-in
voice chat, screen sharing,
uh and then sort of this
um it's very very deeply embedded in the
editor. So, the the like the every
buffer is sort of this um this CRDT,
this like replicated data type that um
you can send these diffs across across
our like protocol, you know.
There is a server, but it's like
effectively peer-to-peer. There's
you synchronize like the diffs that
you're sending and so I can, you know,
hop in a call with Bennett and he can be
moving around, I can follow him, I can
see where he's looking. Maybe he comes
across a function that I don't know, I
can do go to definition on that
resource, split off, join back, and we
can edit the same code, run the same
code.
>> Do you have other huddles as well that
you can do in like Slack and then have
that integration? That's so cool.
>> It's It's basically, you know, we, you
know, we don't use Slack huddle. Like we
we use Slack, but we don't use the
huddles cuz we just like we just hop
into Zed to find people, yeah. And then,
you know, if you alt-tab out of Zed, it
will switch over to screen sharing, so
you can see like, you know, if you're
reviewing a PR, you can you can look at
the browser, that sort of thing.
>> Nice, nice. So, we're here at AI
Engineer, um probably, I'd say,
arguably, the premier event in the world
for for for for developers and AI
engineers to to to visit. What are some
of the conversations that you're having?
What are people interested in? And also,
are you kind of like are you happy with
the with the level of adoption that
people here are are kind of like saying
that they that they that they're using a
various Zed?
>> Yeah, there's a It's been It's been
funny. I've been trying to sell Zed to
people as they walk past and
most of them just say they're already
using it. So, it's
>> [laughter]
>> uh it's made my job quite easy. I think
the
um
a lot of interest in ACP. I think, you
know, from our point of view, ACP is a
way that we can, you know, as a text
editor, we can let you
use cloud code with your familiar key
bindings in your familiar UI, not stuck
in a terminal.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
but for, you know, for other projects,
it's like a way to abstract over agents.
It's a way to, you know, if you want to
send a message, if if you want to write
some code to send a message to 10
different agents and have them compete
to to get to provide the best solution,
you know, ACP's is good choice to do
that. Um
I don't remember the details. I think
open source using ACP just for for for
this for this like abstraction layer.
>> Yeah. And I think I I
JetBrains I think is also
>> Yeah, they're they're working so they're
working with us.
Um they're working with us on ACP. It's
sort of this big collaborative push cuz
like you know
you would think JetBrains and Zed would
be big competitors not but like it's I
think it's in it's in everyone's
interest to have this standard like
like you know I I think the the LSP
parallels are clear like
a world without LSP isn't necessarily
better for anyone develop like it's
>> It's a it's a frenemy frenemy
relationship.
>> Exactly. Yeah, healthy competition.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Um awesome. It's been
great talking with you. What what advice
would you give to any uh agentic
developer out there as maybe an unlock
perhaps that that you feel people don't
really know about these days.
>> I think just just try lots of things.
Just like try everything. Set it up. I
will say this is a nice thing about ACP.
You can just try stuff and you don't
have to get used to a new whole new
environment. But yeah, just just try
lots of things. Things are changing
really quickly.
>> Yeah. And keep keep trying as well
because what you tried one month ago is
probably quite different now.
>> Yeah, it's you know it's Zed is very
different compared to compared to the
beginning of January for sure. Um
yeah, keep keep trying things. Keep
experimenting. See what you like. See
what you don't like. Uh yeah, build some
stuff.
>> Awesome. Cameron, it's been great
chatting. Enjoy the rest of the day.
>> Nice to meet you.
>> Cheers.
Hey, joining me is Nick Arcalona. Nick,
how are you?
>> Uh I'm great. It's great to see you.
>> Absolutely. Likewise. Uh you just came
out of the keynote as well. Uh tell us a
little Actually, first of all, tell us a
little bit about who you were, what you
do, who you work for.
>> Uh yeah, I'm
so I'm the head of AI and research at
Jellyfish. We're Boston-based and uh
we're in the AI observability space
understanding how companies are using
agents to transform their software
engineering teams.
>> met a few times actually. I think in New
York AI DevCon was the was the most
recent.
We've got another one actually June 1st,
2nd. Hopefully you can join us there
maybe in London.
>> Yeah, yeah, I would love to come back.
Yeah, but that was a great event you had
in New York. It was a really fantastic.
Yeah. good to do the event there.
>> Tell us a little bit about the content
here.
You just came out of the keynote. What
was your biggest takeaway?
>> There was some great stuff. The The
Google stuff is very fascinating. You
know, all the things that they're doing
outside of large language models. So,
for instance, the omnimodal embeddings
thing. Like, I would love to have a
model that understands, you know, like
documents on a you know, visual and
spatial and kind of language level at
the same time. The weather stuff was
very cool. And I've been a big fan of
the world model stuff that they've been
doing. So, that was great. And then the
open claws.
That was very spicy. Like, that was a
lot of fun just to see I mean, it's
unprecedented that project, right? So,
just to see
what actually goes on behind the scenes
was very was very interesting.
>> Amazing. Amazing. I see Peter on Twitter
all the time asking for contributions
versus just people asking for things. I
think absolutely need that. What are you
here to learn at AI Engineer?
>> I mean, the biggest thing and why I keep
coming to these events is it's just
everything's moving so fast. So, just
seeing, you know,
the difference between
the where things were a couple months
ago is the most exciting thing for me.
And one of the things I like about
coming to the expo, seeing the talks is,
you know, people say like, "Oh, I
remember coming in like off for MCP like
isn't solved." Then you come back and
there's entire businesses devoted to
that, right? So, just the pace of
innovation where
there's just there's new products, new
open source, new companies popping up to
fill all these holes. And you learn how
these these gaps you didn't know existed
and then you know they exist and then
they're being filled. Like, that that
flywheel is just so rapid, you know.
>> we don't need this once a year. We need
it every month or every other week,
right?
>> Every every quarter. I mean, I've never
had a time in my career where going to
multiple conferences a year was so
valuable. and every time you're learning
all these new things.
>> know you're just going to hear the same
thing.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> What's more important to you? Is it the
Is it the the corridor track here or the
sessions that you go to?
>> Um I mean, you know, the the
>> say if you came here just to talk to me.
That's I'm I'm fine with that, too.
>> Well, you know, it's the it's the kind
of live in-person experience because all
this content is available online and
it's fantastic and you can get it and I
could be watching the live stream at
home. So, the things that you can only
get here by talking to the people. You
go to the after events and actually
hearing cuz it's the stuff when you're
when you're terminally online, you get a
skewed view of what reality is. And when
you talk to someone, you're like, What
How are you
you know, person your personal agents
are building them? How's that going? And
everyone's like, "It's harder than
everyone on Twitter makes it out to be,
all right?"
>> interesting. What do you What are you
finding the level of folks who are
attending AI engineer? Is it Is it
different to that online? Is it Are you
getting the elite people who are, you
know, on the bleeding edge of
technology?
>> Well, it's more just like the Instagram
thing where everybody's putting their
best selves online. And when you talk to
someone face-to-face over a pint, then
you find out like all of these things
are harder like learning new stuff,
changing what we do, and you know,
tinkering with all these things is hard.
And we're all working with like piles of
broken glass and trying to build useful
stuff out of them at the the bleeding
edge of this.
>> Yeah.
>> So, it's tougher than maybe it seems if
you just sit around and and read
everyone's post about how how great I
you know, I
how great my open claw setup is, right?
It's harder than that.
>> Let's Let's Let's end by talking a
little bit about Jellyfish as well.
What's new in the Jellyfish space?
>> I mean, we're you know, I'm I'm very
much on the data side and we're just
excited about all of the new data we're
getting, you know, and it's making its
way into the product very rapidly where,
you know, we used to be focused on
understanding AI adoption and then a lot
on uh kind of productivity and and
transformation. You know, are your teams
getting faster? But now we're getting
very much into the space of
understanding tokens. Um you You what
does effective token usage look like?
What does effective um kind of agentic
engineering look like? Because we're
able to get data and monitor usage and
understand workflows at the token usage
level, at the model level, at the kind
of agent, you know, tool usage level.
So,
really it's understanding, you know,
it's not just about did I use the most
tokens? Like, did I use them well,
right?
>> how many companies today are saying,
"Well, if you're using more if you're
spending more money and using more
tokens, you're adopting AI more." That's
what they're saying.
>> Well, who's who's saying that? That the
people that are selling us the tokens?
>> Uh surprisingly, actually no.
Surprisingly, there are like people
people have targets in organizations to
say, "Look, we need a we need to use AI
more effectively." Well, not more
effectively, we need to grow adoption at
any cost almost. And it's like if great
token usage is almost showing that more
of the business is using it. But the
problem is
what I think you said effective token
usage, right? That's what we're missing.
>> It makes sense to first order, but
you're not going to run an engineering
org based on how much electricity you
use, right? That we use the most
electricity. At At these early stages,
it makes sense, but everyone's going to
want to know
why why you know, if you're not having a
good time, why? Why isn't the machine
working the way that you want? You know,
that's what engineering leaders that's
what they do, you know, so.
>> Nick, it's great to catch up.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Great to see you.
>> Yeah, I'm sure yeah, and I'm sure we'll
we'll we'll bump into each other again
at another conference soon. Enjoy the
rest of AI Engineer.
>> Yeah, you too.
>> Well, that's it for today's episode. I
hope you enjoyed some of the
conversations we had here at AI
Engineering London. Just an incredible
groups of
of intelligent smart people that we've
been chatting with. I loved how many
people really here at this conference to
learn and understand what's new from not
a year ago, but really a week, a month,
a couple of months ago. It's amazing how
fast this industry is changing. And and
really talking to some of the smart
minds here and chatting to people in
person is really what makes the
difference. So, thanks very much to AI
engineer for for having Tess will be
here in person and sponsor
the the conference. And we're also
looking forward to our own conference in
just a couple of months, AI Native
DevCon in London, June 1st, 2nd. Hope to
see you there. Bye for now.
>> The AI Native Dev is brought to you by
Tess. The package manager for skills and
context. Your hosts are Guy Podjarny and
me, Simon Maple. Our producer [music] is
Tom Dawler. The AI Native Dev is not
just a podcast, it's a community. And we
host monthly meetups at the Tess offices
in Central London. Visit
tess.io/community
[music] to learn more and I hope to see
you there.